export const GOVERNMENTA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The study of government is important because it",
A: "directs people’s attention to development of non-state institutions",
B: "enables citizens to understand the processes for managing state affairs",
C: "encourages individuals to make decisions that satisfy their aspirations",
D: "encourages the elite to remain in power",
answer: "B. makes, enforces and interprets laws for the state",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A system of government where political powers are inherited is called",
A: "monarchy",
B: "diarchy",
C: "democracy",
D: "aristocracy",
answer: "B. learn about their rights",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Democracy can be promoted through",
A: "genymandering",
B: "slander",
C: "accountability",
D: "lobbying",
answer: "A. maintain law and order",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The ability to command obedience is called",
A: "authority",
B: "influence",
C: "legitimacy",
D: "mobilization",
answer: "C. organs of government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Legitimacy is determined mainly by",
A: "charisma",
B: "influence",
C: "acceptance",
D: "desire",
answer: "C. organized laws",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following is a feature of democracy?",
A: "Majority rule",
B: "Election by selected adults",
C: "Quick decision making",
D: "Rule by wealthy men",
answer: "B. power",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following is a source of political power?",
A: "Gerrymandering",
B: "Election",
C: "filibuster",
D: "Immunity",
answer: "B. force",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Laws made by the legislative bodies are called",
A: "judiciary review",
B: "statutory laws",
C: "criminal laws",
D: "case law",
answer: "B. legitimacy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Delegated legislation is unpopular because it",
A: "quickens the lawmaking process",
B: "receives wide publicity",
C: "is not made by the legislature",
D: "calters for emergency situations",
answer: "A. legitimate right to exercise political power",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Political socialization begins from",
A: "adulthood",
B: "childhood",
C: "old age",
D: "manhood",
answer: "C. legitimacy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A.V.Dicey popularized the principle of",
A: "rule of law",
B: "democracy",
C: "political culture",
D: "separation of powers",
answer: "D. Jean Bodin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following is the lowest in the hierarchy of feudal system?",
A: "Kinights",
B: "Serfs",
C: "Nobles",
D: "Lords",
answer: "B. electorate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The ratification of major executive decisions by the legislature is in line with the application of",
A: "separation of powers",
B: "rule of law",
C: "checks and balances",
D: "fusion of powers",
answer: "B. International laws",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. In which of the following political systems is rule of law most enhanced?",
A: "Cabinet system",
B: "Feudal system",
C: "Fascist system",
D: "Communist system",
answer: "A. Greece",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A constitution is the",
A: "written document of traditional practices",
B: "functional aspect of government activities",
C: "supreme document of the government",
D: "fundamental laws of the land",
answer: "A. the majority rule and the protection of the minority",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A constitution is important because it",
A: "teaches moral values of the society",
B: "prescribes rules for those who govern",
C: "serves as a source of conflict in society",
D: "describes the laws and admonishes obedience",
answer: "D. Gabriel Almond",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following cannot be found in a constitution?",
A: "Fundamental Human Rights",
B: "Manifestoes of political parties",
C: "Organs of government",
D: "Duties and obligations of citizens",
answer: "B. Cognitive orientation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A rigid constitution is a feature of",
A: "unitary system",
B: "monarchical system",
C: "confederal system",
D: "federal system",
answer: "B. socialization",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In a parliamentary system the executive is weak because it is",
A: "accountable to parliament",
B: "responsible for its own actions",
C: "headed by a prime minister",
D: "the head of state that controls the government",
answer: "C. Communalism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. An advantage of a confederation over a federation is that the component units",
A: "have the right to secede",
B: "share resources equally",
C: "are politically stable",
D: "co-operate fully with the centre",
answer: "B. Tourism (Exposure to different cultures and societies contributes to political socialization.)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Confederalism was once practiced in",
A: "Nigeria and Ghana",
B: "Senegal and The Gambia",
C: "Mali and Cole d’lvoire",
D: "Ghana and Benin",
answer: "A. Private individuals control the economy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following acts as a check on the Executive in the control of the finances of a state? The",
A: "judiciary",
B: "civil service",
C: "press",
D: "legislature",
answer: "D. communism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. In the legislature, carpel-crossing means",
A: "make rules",
B: "formulate decisions",
C: "arrest offenders",
D: "adjudicate cases",
answer: "B. colonialism",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The responsibility of the judiciary is to",
A: "make rules",
B: "formulate decisions",
C: "arrest offenders",
D: "adjudicate cases",
answer: "D. division of labour",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. One of the limitations on freedom of speech is",
A: "libel",
B: "trespassing",
C: "bye-laws",
D: "unlawful detention",
answer: "B. Serfs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A citizen’s duties do not include",
A: "defending the nation",
B: "obeying the laws",
C: "paying taxes",
D: "giving alms to the poor",
answer: "A. hierarchical land ownership between the lords and the serfs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. One-party system leads to",
A: "dictatorship",
B: "democracy",
C: "diarchy",
D: "theocracy",
answer: "D. capitalism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In a democratic state the party system that usually operates is",
A: "Mass pathy",
B: "multi-party",
C: "one-party",
D: "elite party",
answer: "A. fascism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The coming together of two or more political parties to form a government is",
A: "coalition",
B: "merger",
C: "unification",
D: "co-operation",
answer: "A. feudalism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Universal Adult Suffrage is associated with a",
A: "democratic government",
B: "political culture",
C: "public accountability",
D: "political socialization",
answer: "D. A.V.Dicey",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A major advantage of the Secret Ballot System of voting is that",
A: "it is faster than other systems",
B: "it ensures the anonymity of the voter",
C: "it extends the franchise to all adults",
D: "nobody can be prevented from voting",
answer: "B. constitutuent assembly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The ‘first-past-the-post system of voting is also called",
A: "second ballot system",
B: "proportional representation",
C: "simple majority system",
D: "alternative vote system",
answer: "A. judiciary",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Restricted franchise violates the idea of",
A: "political equality",
B: "political culture",
C: "public accountability",
D: "political socialization",
answer: "B. Sovereignty resides in the centre",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following can aid in the formation of public opinion?",
A: "Order-in-council",
B: "free press",
C: "Existence of one-party system",
D: "Existence of press censorship",
answer: "D. Receives foreign dignitaries",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The civil service is an institution for",
A: "carrying out private organization goals",
B: "effecting civil society policies",
C: "formulating and executing public policies",
D: "initiating bureaucratic private agenda",
answer: "C. renunciation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The recruitment of personnel into civil service by the public/civil service commission prevents",
A: "political patronage",
B: "bribery and corruption",
C: "overstaffing",
D: "bureaucracy",
answer: "A. Campaigns and rallies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following manages a public corporation?",
A: "Chambers of Commerce",
B: "Board of Directors",
C: "An Accountant-General",
D: "An Auditor-General",
answer: "B. dominate the political scene",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Local governments are essential because they",
A: "encourage division in a country",
B: "implement government policies at national levels",
C: "make laws for a nation",
D: "train local people in the art of governing",
answer: "D. Plurality system (Plurality systems do not use proportional representation methods.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following delayed nationalist movements in French West Africa?",
A: "Presence of educated elite",
B: "The policy of Assimilation",
C: "The use of local chiefs",
D: "Granting of freedom to Africans",
answer: "D. less government interference",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA) was founded in",
A: "Sierra Leone",
B: "Liberia",
C: "Ghana",
D: "Nigeria",
answer: "B. persistently neglected the advice of his elders",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The west Africa Students Union (WASU) was formed by",
A: "Siaka Stevents",
B: "B.KA Gbedemah",
C: "E.F.Smail",
D: "Oladipo Solanke",
answer: "A. loyalty to one political superior",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Military government usually rule through",
A: "bye-laws",
B: "decrees",
C: "parliament",
D: "statutes",
answer: "A. Governor-General",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. A military coup détat is followed by",
A: "enforcement of fundamental human rights",
B: "suspension of the constitution",
C: "breaking of diplomatic relations with foreign countries",
D: "mass importation of firearms",
answer: "A. source of revenue for colonial administration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following factors influences a country’s foreign policy?",
A: "Size of the country’s civil service",
B: "Overall national interest of the country",
C: "Capacity of the police force",
D: "Type of traditional rulers in the country",
answer: "A. made all French West Africans French citizens",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The Organization of African Unity (OAU) was set up in",
A: "Accra",
B: "Harare",
C: "Cairo",
D: "Addis Ababa",
answer: "A. absorption of French colonial ex-servicemen into the French army",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The organ of the Organization of African Unity (OAU)established for peaceful settlement of disputes is the",
A: "Commission of Mediation Conciliation and Arbitration",
B: "Council of Ministers",
C: "Secretariat",
D: "Assembly of Heads of State and Government",
answer: "A. Nigeria",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "B. National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "C. Setting up of a Constituent Assembly",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The head of the Commonwealth of Nations is the",
A: "Prime Minister",
B: "High Commissioner",
C: "British Foreign Secretary",
D: "British Monarch",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following organs of the United Nations Organization has outlived its usefulness? The",
A: "General Assembly",
B: "Trusteeship Council",
C: "International Court of Justice",
D: "Economic and Social Council",
answer: "A. promote economic development among member states",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]